SAM LAXTON

70 Pinfold Lane, Cheslyn Hay, Walsall, WS6 7NY

07584098704

lacko 6789@hotmail.co.uk

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have recently finished my University of Birmingham Coding Boot Camp while also being employed full time. This 24-week program gave me a total of 1 year of experience of many different technologies which included React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, Bookshelf.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Java, Command Line & Git. We are also required to participate in mini projects with peers from my class.

My GitHub Account Link

Professional Portfolio Link

Favorite projects completed:

- <u>Filmapedia (Mini Project 1)</u> A web app that showcases information about any filmed searched. The web app demonstrates my ability to use a Javascript, CSS & Bulma Framework. Using a GET method to retrieve information using application programming interface (API).
- Rhythm Rater (Mini Project 2) We created an application using JavaScript, Hansdlebars, CSS, DBeaver, MySQL, Docker, Heroku. As a group to create an album review website using Front-end & Back-end for a full stack application.
- <u>SQL Employee Tracker</u> This project was build to demonstrate my ability of using node.js, mysql2, and console.table. Using all of these together has allowed me to explore different avenues within the backend.
- <u>README.md Generator</u> This web application is a README.md generator, this is used to create a high-quality README. I have used the inquirer package, node.js & JavaScript which has allowed me to use questions as prompts, I have then used the answers to the questions to populate the README.md.

My current profession is a Doors and Windows Test Engineer at Element Materials Technology based in Wednesbury. I have 5 years' experience of testing to several different BSI written standards. I write up test reports to allow the client to file for certification, helping them with several different certification bodies such as BM Trada and CertiSecure. I spend a lot of time with customers and giving them the best experience with testing.

I'm looking for a full-stack role within a supportive team at a software focused organization that will give me exposure to all areas of a products development cycle and help me grow into a well-rounded, high-performing software engineer.

MY GOALS

WORK HISTORY

Doors & Windows Test Engineer 05/2017 to Current

Wednesbury, Birmingham

- Working with technical documents such as PAS24 & BS6375-1.
- Managing clients testing and certification needs.
- Training up new and existing test engineers in test standards and which I have over 5 years' experience in.
- Strong eye for detail when reporting and documenting testing.
- Designing new test sheets with updated standard requirements such as EN1191.
- Instrumental in redesigning several EN1191 rigs for a cleaner and easier finish to allow for smoother transitioning when changing for new testing and samples.

Research & Development Apprentice 09/2015 to 05/2017 Dudley, Birmingham

- BTEC completed in 2017 which gave me a Level 3 in Advanced Engineering.
- Completing various tasks to help push the team in the right direction, such as using PLC's to control different spray methods.
- Creating a new working machine from scratch with the manufacturing team.
- Worked along side a team of engineers who were constantly innovating and looking for new ways to streamline different products.

EDUCATION

UG Aff Coding Boot Camp Web Development, **09/2022 – 03/2023 University of Birmingham**

Grade A

Level 3 Extended Engineer Diploma: Research & Development

Apprentice, 08/2017

EEF Technology Centre

PASS

BTEC Level 3 Sport, 05/2017

Black Country University Technical College

Merit

OCR: Principle Learning in Engineering Level 3, 05/2017

Black Country University Technical College

Grade C

GCSE, Various Subjects: 05/2013

Cheslyn Hay Sport & Community High School

GCSE - Mathematics (B)

GCSE - English Literature (C)

GCSE - English Language (C)

BTEC - Sport (Distinction*)

BTEC - Applied Science (Merit)

GCSE - Design & Technology (C)

GCSE - History (D)

ONAT - ICT (Pass)

GCSE - Religious Studies (B)

SKILLS

- Analytical thinker.
- Experience with a range of technologies that include HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, Bookshelf.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Java, Command Line & Git.
- Preparation of final certification reports and with final signature.
- Fork Lift & MWEP Driver.

- Supportive co-worker, supporting and assisting colleagues with learning new tests or help with certification and clients.
- Confident communicator and able to explain complex standard procedures to client.

LINKS & INTERESTS

- GitHub account https://github.com/Lacko3006
- Walks through nature trails, Gym, Football
- · Learning new technologies.
- Listening & producing DJ sets in spare time
- Playing some local gigs for friends and events
- Reading non-fiction books